Guide to the Llewellyn Jones Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Llewellyn Jones papers
1902-1962
YCAL MSS 257
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
3.17
(9 boxes)
The Llewellyn Jones Papers contain correspondence, writings, and other papers that document the professional and personal life of writer and editor Llewellyn Jones.
Jones, Llewellyn, 1884-1961
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from David J. Holmes on the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund, 2002.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 9: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Llewellyn Jones (1884-1961)
Llewellyn Jones was born July 13, 1884 in Castletown in the Isle of Man, Great Britain to John and Katherine Jones. He attended King William's College and the Douglas School of Science. Jones married Susan Warren Wailbus in 1917 and together they had three children: Llewellyn, Cornelia, and George Wilbur. From 1914 to 1932, he was the literary editor of the Chicago Evening Post. During his time as editor, Jones also taught writing as a visiting summer instructor at the University of Chicago in 1924 and 1926; and from 1925 to 1927 he was an instructor of short story writing at Northwestern University. After leaving the Chicago Evening Post, he was editor for Willett, Clark and Company, a Chicago publishing firm. Jones moved to Boston in 1937 to take the position of editor of the Christian Register, but resigned in 1941 due to financial instability and conflict between the Christian Register and the American Unitarian Association.
Jones was a member of the Chicago Literary Club, the Cliff Dwellers of Chicago and PEN, and was President of the Greater Boston American-Scandinavian Forum. He authored books and essays and translated several publications from Danish and Swedish. His books include First Impressions; Essays on Poetry, Criticism, and Prosody (1925); How to Criticize Books (1928); and How to Read Books (1930). Jones was one of thirty-four individuals who signed the 1933 Humanist Manifesto I, written by Roy Wood Sellars and Raymond Bragg. He lived in Cambridge, Massachusetts until his death in 1961.
Scope and Contents
The Llewellyn Jones Papers document his personal and professional life as a writer and editor and span the dates 1902 to 1962. The Papers contain correspondence, writings, and other papers such as financial and business papers, writings of others, and art and music event pamphlets. The bulk of the correspondence regards the Christian Register and the American Unitarian Association, and his involvement in the Chicago literary community; a small portion of the correspondence is personal in nature. The collection also contains documentation of Jones's involvement with the Cliff Dwellers, a Chicago club that supports the fine and performing arts.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into four series: Correspondence, Writings, Professional Papers, and Other Papers.
Humanist manifesto; American literature -- 20th Century; Authors -- 20th Century; Christians -- Massachusetts -- Newspapers; Newspaper publishing -- United States; Unitarianism; Authors; Fite, Warner, 1867-1955; Jones, Llewellyn, 1884-1961; Masters, Edgar Lee, 1868-1950; American Unitarian Association; American-Scandinavian Foundation; Chicago Daily News, Inc; Chicago Post Company; Christian Herald Association; Christian Register Office; Cliff Dwellers (Club); Humanist Press Association
- Correspondence, 1902-1960, undated; Series I; 2.09; (5 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Series I, Correspondence, is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. A small amount of general, unidentified and third party correspondence is filed at the end of the series.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains letters to Llewellyn Jones from colleagues and friends. The letters discuss Jones's writings and work as editor of the Chicago Evening Post and the Christian Register, as well as his activities in the Chicago Literary Club and the Greater Boston American-Scandinavian Forum. A small portion of the letters regard his personal life.
  There is extensive correspondence with the philosopher and author Warner Fite, whose letters discuss individualism and humanism. Jones's editorial and professorial involvement in the literary world is documented through his correspondence with prominent writers such as Carl Sandburg, Margaret Anderson, Lillian Hellman, Amy Lowell, Edgar Lee Masters, Harriet Monroe, Janet Lewis, and Yvor Winters.
  Letters from the Humanist Press Association express support for Jones's position at the Christian Register. Additional correspondence regarding the Christian Register is filed in Series III, Professional Papers.
  - Alden, Raymond, 1915, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American-Scandinavian Foundation, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Anderson, Margaret, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Argus Book Shop, 1939, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Association of Arts and Industries, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bates, Katherine Lee, 1917-1918 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bay, J. Christina, 1937-1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Beers, James, 1952-1956 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bentley, Arthur, 1950-1955, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bestercey, Ilona, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Includes drafts of "Our Marriage Feast" and "I Am No Sister to the Lorelei"
  - Bodenheim, Maxwell, 1924, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Includes translations of "Night" and "Drunk"
  - Books Abroad, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Botker, C., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Boyer, Joe, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bradley, Sam, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Includes offprint of "Every Man I Know"
  - Brigham, Edward, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Includes drawing and recital pamphlet
  - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Browne, Maurice, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Brownell, Baker, 1928-1960 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Burke, Thomas, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Century of Progress International Exposition (1933-1934: Chicago, Ill.) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Chicago Daily News
    See: North, Sterling
  - Chicago Literary Club, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Christian Herald, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Crapsey, Adelaide, 1916-1930, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Dennis, Geoffrey, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Deutch, Elinor, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Dick, Viola M., 1958 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Dillon, George, 1926-1931 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Dimnet, E., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Donahey, Mary, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Dow, Dorothy, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Eberhart, Nelle Richmond, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Includes draft of "The Silver Syllables"
  - Eckstein, Gustav, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Eliot, Frederick, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Includes clipping
  - Elliot, Bert, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Fanning, Carolyn, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Farrar and Rinehart Publishers, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Farrell, Vincent, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Field, Susan Bard, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Fite, Warner, 1924-1939 (Box 1, Folder 40-42)
    Includes drafts of Fite's work
  - Fite, Warner, 1940-1948, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Freeland Colony
    See: Horr, Alexander
  - Friends of American Writers, 1929, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    Includes outline of plan for literary foundation
  - Garland, Hamlin, 1922, 1926, undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
    Includes lecture advertisement
  - Gedin, Lena, undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Girelus, Charles, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Glick, Annie, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Golden Cockerel Press, 1931, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
    Includes printed note
  - Golowanjuk, Jascha, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Goodwyn Institute
    See: Ogilvie, Clarence
  - Greene, Alexander, 1933-1941 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Hacker, Francis, 1914-1924 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Haldeman, Julius E., 1933-1944 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Hansen, Einar, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Hardin, Floyd, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Harper and Brothers, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Harper, Samuel, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Harris, Frank, undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Hellman, Lillian, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Henrickson, Carl Rose, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Hervey, John, 1916-1932 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Hoirup, Henning, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Holden, Raymond, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Hook, Sydney, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Horr, Alexander, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Huebsch, B.W., 1917-1959 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Humanist Press Association, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Humill, Alfred Ernest, undated (Box 2, Folder 69)
    Signed "Hugh Western"
  - Humphries, Rolfe, undated (Box 2, Folder 70)
    Draft, typescript, "To a Strange Woman"
  - Hunter, Dard, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Jahn, Ursula, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Jarett, Lew, 1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Jones, Katherine and "Gladys" (outgoing only), undated (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Kaufman, Walter, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Kenton, Edna, undated (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Alfred A. Knopf Inc., 1961 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Koch, Hal, 1947-1952, undated (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Kreymborg, Alfred, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - La Selle, Toni, 1934, 1950-1951, undated (Box 2, Folder 80)
    Includes press release
  - Lahmer, Margery, 1926-1929, undated (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Laughlin, James
    See: New Directions Publishing Corp.
  - Leonard, W. E., 1910-1915 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Levine, Isaac, 1916-1952 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Lewis, E.H., 1916-1932 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Lewis, Janet, 1930-1941 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Lewisohn, Ludwig, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Lichtenstein, Walter, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Linner, Sven, 1949-1951 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Little Review
    See: Anderson, Margaret
  - Lothrop, Rachel, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Lovett, Robert Morse, 1928-1935, undated (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Lowell, Amy, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Lowry, Russell, 1907, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Lychenheim, Morris, undated (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - MacDowell Society of Chicago, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1925-1359 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    Includes draft, typescript, corrected, of "Archibald MacLeish: A Modern Metaphysical" by Llewellyn Jones
  - Marsh, Daniel, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Masters, Edgar Lee, 1916-1923, undated (Box 3, Folder 97)
    Includes photograph of Emma J. Masters and draft, typescript, " Transfusion"
  - Mavor, James W., 1953-1958 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Mayfield, John, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Meyer, Edith Patterson, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Menninger, Karl, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Middletown, Scudder, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    Includes reprint of poem "1918"
  - Monroe, Harriet, undated (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Morani, Lloyd and Mary, 1953-1957 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Morris, Charles C. (outgoing only), undated (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - William Morrow and Company, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Mowry, Emily Wardwell, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    Includes advertisement
  - Munro, Harold, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Murdock, Kenneth, 1951-1959 (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Neumann, Henry, 1957-1959, undated (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Neutch, Henry, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - New Directions Publishing Corp., 1948, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - New Review, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - North, Sterling, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - W.E. Norton and Company, Inc., 1928 (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - O'Connor, Tom, 1953-1954, undated (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Ogilvie, Clarence, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - Omond, T.S., 1920-1922 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    Includes clippings
  - Osborn, C.S., 1925-1928 (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - Otto, M.C., 1924-1940, undated (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - Pearce, Helen, 1926-1929, undated (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - Percy, Bliss, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - Percy, William Alexander, 1915-1932 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    Includes reprint of "Three Poems"
  - Pfeffer, Nat, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - Poetry Bookshop
    See: Munro, Harold
  - Post, Louis and Alice, 1912-1914 (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - Powys, Llewellyn, 1922-1923 (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - Quarrie Corporation Publishers, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - Ransom, John Crowe, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - Ribal, Lillian, 1931, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - Roberts, Sara, undated (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Sabsay, Nahum, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - Sandburg, Carl, 1927, 1936, undated (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - Schulkind, Adelaide, 1941, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - Scott, Evelyn, 1921, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - Scottword, Charles Erskine, 1928-1932 (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - Sherman, Stuart, undated (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - Simon, H.F., 1923, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - Sinclair, John and Katharine, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 138)
    Includes photograph
  - Society of Midland Authors
    See: Donahey, Mary
  - Solle's Bookshop, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    Includes statement
  - Sorokin, P.A., 1940-1941 (Box 4, Folder 140)
  - Spingarn, J.E., 1919-1926, undated (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - Squire, J.C., 1914-1921 (Box 4, Folder 142)
  - Stephan, Ruth, 1947, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 143)
  - Stern, Edith, 1927-1930, undated (Box 4, Folder 144)
  - Stockton, Esther, 1922-1924, undated (Box 4, Folder 145)
  - Strayer, Paul Moore, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 146)
  - Sudler, Culbreth, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 147)
  - Sugitani, M., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 148)
  - Szulsaski, S., 1915 (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - Tegen, Grunhild, 1943-1956, undated (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - Tietjins, Eunice, 1915-1952, undated (Box 4, Folder 151)
    Includes poem draft, typescript, corrected, and photographs
  - United States. Court of Appeals, 1938-1943 (Box 4, Folder 152)
  - Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1916-1922 (Box 4, Folder 153)
  - Untermeyer, Louis, 1914-1953, undated (Box 4, Folder 154)
  - Warren, Edward Perry, 1917, 1922, undated (Box 4, Folder 155)
    Includes "O Gate of Life Immortal," song, words and music by Edward Perry Warren, printed score
  - Warren, Fiske, 1917-1943, undated (Box 4, Folder 156)
    Includes four negatives, one photograph, and third party correspondence
  - Webster, Henry Kitchell, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 157)
  - Weed, Alma, undated (Box 4, Folder 158)
  - Wheelock, John Hall, 1922-1928 (Box 4, Folder 159)
  - Who's Who in Massachusetts, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 160)
    Includes entry clipping
  - Wick, Jean, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 161)
  - Empty folder (Box 4, Folder 162)
  - Wilson, Ed, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 163)
  - Wing, DeWitt, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 164)
  - Winters, Yvor, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 165)
  - Wright, John Lloyd, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 166)
  - Young, G.A., 1939 (Box 4, Folder 167)
  - Young, Stark, 1928, 1946, undated (Box 4, Folder 168)
  - Zesbough, Helen, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 169)
  - Zipf, Oscar, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 170)
  - General correspondence, A-Z, 1902-1960, undated (Box 5, Folder 171-175)
  - ___, Craig, undated (Box 5, Folder 176)
    Includes writing drafts, typescript
  - ___, Hortense, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 177)
  - ___, Marjorie, 1919, undated (Box 5, Folder 177a)
  - ___, Regina, undated (Box 5, Folder 178)
  - ___, Sara, 1925-1926, undated (Box 5, Folder 179)
  - Unidentified, 1917-1951 (Box 5, Folder 180-184)
    Includes "William Shakespeare and Fulke Greville: An Introductory Chapter," draft, typescript and photograph of "J"
  - Third party correspondence, 1932-1941 (Box 5, Folder 185)
- Writings, 1962, undated; Series II; 14
  The series is arranged into two subseries: Titled Writings and Untitled Writings. The first is arranged alphabetically by title. The second is arranged alphabetically by subject headings written by Jones at the top of each draft.
  Series II, Writings, contains untitled and titled writings by Llewellyn Jones. The bulk of the writings are untitled drafts of articles that Jones identified by subject, and that were most likely written for the Chicago Evening Post. Included among the untitled writings is a draft on novels "from 1833 to the present, in which Chicago has been the heroine." Titled writings are primarily undated drafts that include "First Books in a Victorian Boyhood," an autobiographical piece on the books that Jones read as a child.
  - Titled works
    - "Archibald MacLeish: A Modern Metaphysical," includes draft, typescript, corrected
      See: MacLeish, Archibald
    - "First Books in a Victorian Boyhood," draft, typescript, corrected, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 186)
    - "A New Chapter," draft, holograph, undated (Box 5, Folder 187)
    - "Psychoanalysis and Creative Literature," draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 5, Folder 188)
    - "The Romance Behind Business," draft, typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 189)
  - Untitled works, undated
    - Architecture, undated (Box 5, Folder 190)
    - Chicago literature, undated (Box 5, Folder 191)
    - Dickens, Charles, undated (Box 5, Folder 192)
    - Goiters, undated (Box 5, Folder 193)
    - "Hist. church", undated (Box 5, Folder 194)
    - LaFayette, Marquis de, undated (Box 5, Folder 195)
    - Moffett, George, undated (Box 5, Folder 196)
    - "Sun nite street", undated (Box 5, Folder 197)
    - Wright, Frank Lloyd, undated (Box 5, Folder 198)
    - Unidentified, draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 5, Folder 199-200)
- Professional Papers, 1934-1954, undated; Series III
  Series III, Professional Papers, is organized into two subseries: Christian Register and American Unitarian Association. Each subseries is arranged to reflect the original organization by Jones.
  The first subseries consists of Christian Register correspondence, financial and business papers, printed material, and an editorial by Llewellyn Jones documenting his editorship of the paper. Christian Register correspondence includes letters welcoming Jones as editor, article submissions, criticism, and letters discussing the tension between the American Unitarian Association and the Christian Register under Jones's leadership. For example, a letter from Mirium Penny Jacker discusses the tension between Unitarians and conservatism; a letter from Gerald FitzPatrick criticizes Jones's financial judgement; and a letter from Guy Shipler discusses Jones's leaving the paper. Much of the correspondence discusses Frederick Eliot, President of the American Unitarian Association, who became editor following Jones's resignation and shifted control of the Christian Register to the American Unitarian Association. There is also a small amount of third party correspondence. Other letters regarding the Christian Register are found throughout Series I, Correspondence.
  In "A Statement by the Editor," a handwritten editorial, Jones discusses the American Unitarian Association.
  The second subseries consists of correspondence and printed material regarding American Unitarian Association concerns and activities. Correspondence is from various Unitarian churches, their members, and the American Unitarian Association. The letters include comments on Llewellyn Jones's writings; requests for Jones to speak and write book reviews; meeting proceedings; and expressions of disappointment and solidarity regarding his resignation as editor of the Christian Register. Printed material includes church service programs and bulletins, a clipping, and a photograph postcard of the First Parish Church in Bedford, Mass.
  - Christian Register
    - Correspondence, 1938-1941, undated (Box 6, Folder 201-203)
    - Budgets, subscription and circulation statements, meeting agenda, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 204)
    - "A Statement by the Editor," draft, holograph, undated (Box 6, Folder 205)
    - Articles about the Christian Register, 1939, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 206)
  - American Unitarian Association, 1934-1954, undated
    - Correspondence, 1934-1954, undated (Box 6, Folder 207)
    - Printed material, 1937-1940 (Box 6, Folder 208)
- Other Papers, 1915-1962, undated; Series IV
  The series is organized into three subseries: Cliff Dwellers Materials, Writings of Others, and Other Papers.
  Cliff Dwellers Materials includes announcements, correspondence, printed material and newsletters for events and proceedings of the Cliff Dwellers, a club of writers, artists and musicians in Chicago. Announcements include mailings for John Jacob Niles performances, festivals and dances, chamber performances, art exhibitions, and parties.
  Other Papers includes a handbill for Llewellyn Jones's lectures, and literary and music materials of interest to Jones. This subseries also includes handbills, a check invoice, brochures, announcements, holiday cards, a review of Jones's "Chicago Triad," clippings, and a photograph.
  - Cliff Dwellers Materials
    - Announcements, 1933-1960, undated (Box 6, Folder 209-210)
    - Correspondence and printed material, 1934-1952 (Box 6, Folder 211)
    - Newsletters, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 212)
  - Writings of Others
    - Austen, Nat. "Patriotism" and "Fragment of a Night Spent in Chicago," drafts, typescript and holograph, corrected, undated (Box 6, Folder 213)
    - Bogan, Louise. "Exhortation," draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 6, Folder 214)
    - Bosworth, Roger D. "The Voice of a New Faith," draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 6, Folder 215)
    - Burnham, Irene H. "Beauty in the Common Day," brochure, undated (Box 6, Folder 216)
    - Burroughs, John. "Waiting," poem printed on cardstock, undated (Box 6, Folder 217)
    - Childers, Mary Alden. "To Adversity," draft, holograph, undated (Box 6, Folder 218)
    - de la Mare, Walter. The Listeners. New York: Henry Holt and Company, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 219)
      Includes inscription, photograph, and letter from Jones's mother, and poem draft, typescript, annotated
    - Dhone, Ihliam. "Censorship for America?" draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 6, Folder 220)
    - Humpendunck, Otto. Extract from "The Death Pangs of Theism," draft, typescript, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 221)
    - Lana, ___. "Messages to Athenian Leaders," draft, typescript, signed, undated (Box 6, Folder 222)
    - Lewis, Herbert. "Michael Angelo, A.B., A.M., PhD." draft, typescript, undated (Box 6, Folder 223)
    - Marsh, C. Benjamin. "One Year's Failure of the 'New Deal'," speech, typescript, undated (Box 7, Folder 224)
    - Plov, Jaegermester. Untitled, draft, typescript, 1937 Mar 24 (Box 7, Folder 225)
    - Ruin, Hans. "Transformations of the Beautiful," reprint from The Journal of Aesthetics and Art Criticism, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 226)
    - Unidentified. "Excerpts from reports on Llewellyn Jones's 'Chicago Triad'," draft, typescript, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 227)
    - Unidentified. "Love's Epitaph," draft, typescript, undated (Box 7, Folder 228)
  - Other Papers
    - "Lectures by Llewellyn Jones," handbill, circa 1923 (Box 7, Folder 229)
    - Review of Llewellyn Jones's "How to Read Books," clipping, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 230)
    - American-Scandinavian Foundation, check invoice for book review of "Danish Rebel" by Johannes Knudsen, undated (Box 7, Folder 231)
    - Chicago Literary Club, meeting announcement, 1933 Nov 27 (Box 7, Folder 232)
    - Chicago Little Theatre, "A Midsummer's Night's Dream," playbills, 1915 (Box 7, Folder 233)
    - Chubb, Elmer. Lecture advertisements, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 234)
    - Illinois Vigilance Association, pamphlets and newsletter, 1927, undated (Box 7, Folder 235)
    - Jonson Gallery, University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, NM, brochure, 1954, undated (Box 7, Folder 236)
    - Literary and music event invitations, programs, tickets, and handbills, 1915-1935 (Box 7, Folder 237)
    - Photograph of a portrait painting of unidentified woman, undated (Box 7, Folder 238)
- Oversize
  - Unidentified (Series I), 1917-1951 (Box 8, Folder 239)
- Restricted Fragile
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.